<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-16T16:20:49+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Why I Left Marketing to Learn Coding – Luke Stenis: Austin Coding Academy Alumni Spotlight</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/alumni-spotlight/luke-stenis/why-i-left-marketing-to-learn-coding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Left Marketing to Learn Coding – Luke Stenis: Austin Coding Academy Alumni Spotlight" /><published>2019-04-13T19:23:55+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T19:23:55+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/alumni-spotlight/luke-stenis/why-i-left-marketing-to-learn-coding-luke-stenis-austin-coding-academy-alumni-spotlight</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/alumni-spotlight/luke-stenis/why-i-left-marketing-to-learn-coding/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;self-confessed-austin-coding-academy-brand-fanatic-luke-stenis-on-why-he-decided-to-leave-marketing-learn-coding-and-teach-others-to-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-confessed Austin Coding Academy ‘brand fanatic’ Luke Stenis on why he decided to leave marketing, learn coding, and teach others to code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A native of Oklahoma, Luke Stenis originally moved to Austin for grad school. Falling in love with the city - and his future wife - he stayed to start a family, and a career. I asked him what he does for fun. ‘Sunday league soccer with Cameron Road United, the most interesting team in Austin,’ he replies, with a grin. He also plays bass, and has been in several local bands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receiving a Masters in Advertising from UT’s College of Communications, he dabbled in traditional agency work and media research, finally landing in digital marketing. ‘I enjoyed the challenges of copywriting for the web,’ he says. ‘I loved helping tell marketing stories and drive audience behavior.’ Marketing is a ferocious game, however - the pressure is on to continually upsell and cross-sell campaigns to squeeze out that one last dollar. After eight years, he decided he was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-learned-to-code&quot;&gt;Why I learned to Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Strategy Director, he was working very closely with the Engineering and IT departments, improving the website. Together, they optimized conversion funnels - the advertising term for a customer’s journey from a web search or ad, through an e-commerce website, and finally to a sale. ‘I understood the basics, but was never in the trenches myself,’ he explains. He was tired of continually waiting in a queue for issue tickets to be resolved. ‘I wanted to learn how to solve these UX/UI problems myself’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laid off in March of 2015, he realized he no longer had the ‘bellyfire’ passion for marketing. Tired of his ethics and morals being tested, he longed for ‘a career with long-term stability and a more learning-centric foundation’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-the-decision-to-learn-coding&quot;&gt;Making the Decision to Learn Coding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He used his ‘extensive experience in digital marketing to find ACA via Google search’, he says, laughing. As a young father supporting his family, being able to learn to code without quitting his interim bill-paying job was key. ‘It perfectly fit my lifestyle,’ he explains. ‘The school is flexible but still maintains a high level of authenticity’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Learning how to code and approach problem-solving has changed my life,’ says Luke passionately. His favorite thing about coding is also one of the most frustrating. ‘There are correct ways to do things with code. There are also different ways you use code to solve a problem,’ he explains. ‘Sometimes short term solutions can create long term inefficiencies’. Creating well-constructed projects isn’t just about the code required to make them work straight away. According to Luke, the challenge when approaching code issues is to think long-term, and to fix defects in a way that won’t hinder future improvements or projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thinking-like-a-developerengineer&quot;&gt;Thinking Like a Developer/Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s applying these skills to his life in more than just a work setting. ‘I now approach everything in life like code. Assess the problem, look at the end goal, plan each step, and execute with detail and confidence.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke is now an instructor at ACA - a career that he loves. He spends his days as a full time developer and spends his evenings paying it forward to students, teaching tAfter meeting the school’s founders, Chris Sica and Luke Filipos, and completing the beginner, intermediate and advanced classes, he ‘became a huge brand fanatic!’ - which appears to be marketing speak for ‘I’m a fan!’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving a stagnant career to learn coding was the best thing Luke says he’s ever done. ‘My life has really come into focus and its path has never been more clear’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-is-a-lot-to-gain-from-learning-how-to-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a lot to gain from learning how to code&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;our coding program&lt;/a&gt; and revamp your career with impressive new skills.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Luke Stenis decided to quit marketing and learn how to code. Ready why, and how that decision has changed his life:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Choose a Coding Bootcamp that Teaches You More Than Just Code</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/choose-a-coding-bootcamp-that-teaches-you-more-than-just-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Choose a Coding Bootcamp that Teaches You More Than Just Code" /><published>2019-04-13T18:57:29+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T18:57:29+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/choose-a-coding-bootcamp-that-teaches-you-more-than-just-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/choose-a-coding-bootcamp-that-teaches-you-more-than-just-code/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been involved with Austin Coding Academy since its inception many, many moons ago. I’ve taken the coding bootcamp journey both as a student and as an instructor, and I’ve helped class after class of students go from complete novices to completely job-ready in the course of nine months, with varying degrees of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might surprise you, but in most cases the students with the best coding chops didn’t necessarily land the best gig upon graduating our program. Now don’t get me wrong, all Austin Coding Academy graduates are good hires, but in the dawn of our program, some students lacked a full understanding of what it truly takes to be a successful web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Austin Coding Academy, we practice what we preach: &lt;strong&gt;Never stop learning&lt;/strong&gt;. We analyzed what was helping some students transition more successfully into a junior web development role, and what was causing some to stumble out of the gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we found was that software companies, start-ups, and tech giants also desire candidates with a certain combination of soft skills. We were teaching the hard skills – coding languages, concepts, and techniques – but we needed to put more emphasis on soft skills like collaboration and critical-thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Junior web developers who are proficient in these three soft skills find success and are able to accelerate their coding career faster than even the best technical developers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teamwork--leadership-skills&quot;&gt;Teamwork &amp;amp; Leadership Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started applying for dev jobs, my mentor gave me sage wisdom: walk through the engineering area - if developers are sitting silently in rows of cubicles with headphones on, turn and walk away. Great software is usually not written by one person, but by a team. A web development team is made up of different types of people in different types of roles, and sometimes collaboration and teamwork is loud… and messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most developers will also collaborate cross-departmentally throughout their project cycles, with needs to sync with designers, marketers, copywriters, or even managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first day of class, students are placed into learning groups where they collaborate and work together on their first website project outside of class. We have found that students who collaborate and compromise well with others thrive in group work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course of our 10-week classes, students who are successful also have a firm grasp on their time management. While we pride ourselves on a flexible program you can complete without quitting your day job, the coursework is no joke. You will need to hone your time management skills down to a science in order to master this soft skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;critical-thinking-and-problem-solving-skills&quot;&gt;Critical-Thinking and Problem-Solving Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most educational resources for coding follows the same process - choose a language to learn, teach you the syntax, and dive into concepts and theories. What it won’t teach you is how to solve problems or design the process for an entire project, which is why most of us learn how to code in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already started learning to code, you know that it’s not easy. Part of the reason is that code is actually a tool, not a goal. To really learn how to code effectively, start by finding a problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve designed our coursework and classroom environment to help students develop the skills they need to properly assess a problem, conduct thorough online research, and design logic (and code) that solves the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;branding-and-marketing-skills&quot;&gt;Branding and Marketing Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want a (better) career in tech? Good, but you are not alone. Folks are flocking to the web development field and competition for jobs can be stiff. The problem I’ve seen is that most junior web developers don’t know how to or don’t even realize they need to be actively marketing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I transitioned into web development, I spent a decade developing and running marketing campaigns. Here are the three soft skills we teach in tandem with code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-build-your-personal-brand&quot;&gt;Bonus: Build Your Personal Brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branding is about establishing a consistent message about yourself that is recognized by some repeated stimulus (online profiles, resume, portfolio) which when seen reminds the reader of the message. You may have a logo of your initials or a “doing business as” name you want to be identified as professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you are transitioning from a salesperson to web developer, you want to position yourself as a Junior Web Developer transitioning from a sales background. It will be imperative that you spin your past experience to support any soft skills you can gained from sales that are applicable to your new career. Here are a couple quick tips to help you with that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-a-consistent-online-presence&quot;&gt;Create a Consistent Online Presence:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve established your branding, positioning, and consistent messaging, make sure it’s used in your online portfolio, social media profiles, and any resumes you have living on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, use the same profile picture for Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. Keep your posts professionally-minded - if you can be found on Facebook by your name, it’s a safe bet every recruiter or hiring manager has seen your photos from Cinco De Mayo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-your-network--off-line&quot;&gt;Build Your Network – Off-line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re on LinkedIn and have a great network built-up online. That’s a great start! But now the hard part: Networking in real life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best jobs I’ve gotten in my career and every good opportunity has been a result of someone in my network either bringing an opportunity to me or helping me get my foot in the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are looking for a job, you are essentially trying to sell yourself to someone. That may be great for the student who was a former salesperson, but not for everyone else. The next time you are trying to land a new gig, wouldn’t it be nice if you could just reach out to someone you know rather than sending cold emails or making cold calls?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a network isn’t hard but it does take effort. You should have the mindset of always networking. Every new person you meet, every person you interact with online is potentially someone who can become part of your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, our students already have a head start on the first day of class. Not only do students have a robust network of current students, they also have access to our pool of alumni mentors and a non-stop events calendar of networking events and field trips to startups and tech companies around the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t just teach you how to code at Austin Coding Academy, we also teach you the soft skills you need to succeed in the diverse environment of a web development job. If you are interested in learning both the hard and soft skills necessary for a coding career, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;ACA’s course offerings.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get started learning how to code and much more with Austin Coding Academy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fill out an application to reserve your spot in the next class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Software companies, start-ups, and tech giants aren't just looking for coders. Junior web developers who are proficient in these three soft skills find success and are able to accelerate their coding career faster than even the best technical developers:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Awesome Apps You Can Create with C#</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/2017/05/17/5-awesome-apps-you-can-create-with-c-sharp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Awesome Apps You Can Create with C#" /><published>2019-04-13T18:16:59+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T18:16:59+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/2017/05/17/5-awesome-apps-you-can-create-with-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/2017/05/17/5-awesome-apps-you-can-create-with-c-sharp/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is written by Austin Coding Academy graduate and former instructor, Luke Stenis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an Implementation Engineer with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious about what the C# programming language can do? Here is a short introduction to C# and five amazing apps you can build with this technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language-in-the-key-of-c&quot;&gt;Language in the Key of C#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# (pronounced See-Sharp) is a popular and modern programming language created by Microsoft in 2000 alongside their .NET framework. They wanted a more flexible language to build a variety of secure and robust modern applications for Windows, web servers, tablets, and phones. It is now arguably one of the most valuable programming languages in the world to know, and even had a mascot named Andy, who has now since retired in the green pastures of Mascot Hills, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is an object-oriented programming language that is commonly used with Microsoft’s .NET framework. Many of the advantages and features of C# are tied closely to .NET, which is why we teach them together in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/csharp/&quot;&gt;C# courses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# applications and programs run on top of the .NET framework, so that whatever you create can take advantage of the services and programming interfaces that the framework provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These programming interfaces include the ability to save information in a database, read information from an XML file, as well as cryptography, configuration, network communications and all the basic core features that nearly every application or program needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-learn-c&quot;&gt;Why You Should Learn C#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is a useful and flexible language with very expressive syntax that is easy and simple to learn. It shares many similarities with other object-oriented languages, and if you are also familiar with C, C++, or Java, you should pick it up very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of third party apps in the Windows app store are written in C#, and is widely considered the future of Windows application distribution. In short, C# has a very bright future within the Windows universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being productive in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/jobs?q=C%23+Net+Developer&amp;amp;l=Texas&quot;&gt;C# can also land you a job&lt;/a&gt;. The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) is predicting that between 2014 - 2024, employment of software developers is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/computer-and-information-technology/software-developers.htm&quot;&gt;projected to grow 17 percent from 2014 to 2024&lt;/a&gt;, much faster than the average for all occupations. The median annual wage for software developers was&lt;a href=&quot;https://money.usnews.com/careers/best-jobs/software-developer/salary&quot;&gt; $101,790 in 2017.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# jobs are abundant and pay well, and if you are fluent in C# and the .NET framework, you can create some awesome technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-can-create-with-c&quot;&gt;What You Can Create with C#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use C# to build just about anything: business applications, games, web apps, and mobile/tablet apps. Here are five awesome applications you can build with C# code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-video-games&quot;&gt;1. Video Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is extremely popular in many sectors of the gaming industry. You can use C# to quickly develop games for Windows, Android, iOS, and Mac OS X. One of the most popular game-developing platforms is Unity, and C# is one of the most common and easiest programming languages you can use in the Unity environment. A few games built in Unity using C# are: Bastion, Shadowrun Returns, Rust, Wasteland 2, and Hearthstone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in developing video games, learning C# and becoming a C# Unity Developer is a popular and successful path for many video game developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-anti-hacking-software&quot;&gt;2. Anti-Hacking Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world now rich in cyber attacks, major hacks, and an urgent need to keep sensitive information safe, it comes as no surprise that companies, government, and financial institutions are scrambling to bulk with their cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter software developer stage left. These entities are bulking up their development teams with engineers strong in C# .NET technology to build and improve security software that keeps the likes of Wikileaks, Anonymous, and any potential ransomware from maliciously hacking into their and - sometimes - your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-windows-apps-ie-microsoft-office-skype-photoshop&quot;&gt;3. Windows Apps (i.e.: Microsoft Office, Skype, Photoshop)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise that Microsoft’s C# and .NET framework is used primarily to create Windows client applications. Today, Windows Forms and Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) are two major technologies used to develop client applications. (link ‘used to… applications”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb655895&quot; title=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb655895&quot;&gt;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb655895&lt;/a&gt;(v=vs.90).aspx)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;examples-of-windows-applications&quot;&gt;Examples of Windows Applications:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel and so on)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skype&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio 2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL Server 2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paintbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that you won’t be developing for just Windows computers. You can write applications using the C# codebase to run on both Windows and Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-mobile-apps&quot;&gt;4. Mobile Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# is regarded in many development circles as the best language for mobile app development. You can build native mobile apps for multiple platforms – Android, iOS, and Windows devices – on a shared C# codebase. Yes, this means you are also creating an app that works and looks awesome on an iPhone, thanks to Xamarin, a framework that uses native API calls and native platform controls. (Link for “Xamarin”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xamarin.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.xamarin.com/&quot;&gt;https://www.xamarin.com/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-few-examples-of-mobile-apps-written-in-c&quot;&gt;A few examples of mobile apps written in C#:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insightly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinterest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tableau&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The World Bank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cinemark&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NBCUniversal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FoxSports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aviva&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taxfyle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-windows-store-apps&quot;&gt;5. Windows Store Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows store apps were introduced by Windows 8, which coincides with the rise of C#’s popularity. Coincidence? I’ll let you be the judge. Windows store apps are different than mobile app development, and are built primarily using C# and XAML. XAML is used to build app screens and C# is used to run in the backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These apps have features like Touch, messages, tile and swipe, and work on all Windows devices - PCs, tablet, phones, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-to-learn-c-and-the-net-framework&quot;&gt;Where to Learn C# and the .NET Framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C# and the .NET framework are a very mature and powerful technologies that enable you to create applications compatible across any device or operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to change careers or coding languages, learning how to code C# opens up endless possibilities for your job prospects, app ideas and project scope. With the demand for C# developers on the rise over the next decade, there is no better time to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We teach this very technology at Austin Coding Academy. If you are interested in learning how to code C#, check out ACA’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/csharp/&quot;&gt;C# curriculum&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fill out an application to reserve your spot in the next class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Curious about what the C# programming language can do? Here is a short introduction to C# and five amazing apps you can build with this technology stack.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Free Coding Websites for Beginners: Learn How to Code without the Cost</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/5-free-coding-websites-for-beginners/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Free Coding Websites for Beginners: Learn How to Code without the Cost" /><published>2019-04-13T03:43:48+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-13T03:43:48+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/5-free-coding-websites-for-beginners-learn-how-to-code-without-the-cost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/5-free-coding-websites-for-beginners/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will cover some great coding websites for beginners and where to find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has turning points in their lives, and many times we don’t realize we’ve made them until we are well down the road. Other times, we face a tough decision knowing full well that it could take us down two distinctly different paths, altering our lives all together and sending significant ripples through the space-time continuum, opening new dimensions that expose humanity to an otherwise oblivious and belligerent alien race, who in turn decide our planet is perfect for a new galactic freeway-side diner… and you’re on the menu! No pressure, homie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress. At this time last year, I faced a tough decision in my life. I was laid off, with a young family, and a burnt-out candle of a career. I spent the last eight years in Austin’s digital marketing scene, but it wasn’t satisfying, like that feeling you get sitting silently in a public restroom reflecting upon your regrettable choice of Chinese food, all the while listening to the guy in the stall next to you talk to his mother on his cell phone… “You’re a grown man, Chuck!” Get me outta here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind was thirsty for a new challenge, something that balanced creativity, critical thinking, and a technically-sustainable skill. I wanted a new career path that was rewarding, not only financially but intellectually as well. I wanted to create and build stuff on the internet. I had taught myself basic HTML at past jobs – editing email templates with new images, copy, and updating simple styling. After a few meet-ups, online chats and coffee talks within my professional network, I was convinced that learning how to code was a big part of my answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step from there was to look for a more structured learning model, but I was unemployed so it needed to be cheap. Or free. Luckily, there are now ways to get introduced to computer programming without the cost of attending a University or intensive trade school. Many coding websites for beginners now offer free lessons and tutorials for learning how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to advance your career, supplement your skill set, or just love to learn, these five websites below offer instant and interactive courses to teach you programming languages… for free. Trust me, I’m not only a sponsor (not really), I’m also a member (really)…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;codecademy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;CODECADEMY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far the most well-known of the coding websites for beginners on this list, Codecademy.com offers well-structured, interactive courses covering the basics in Web Fundamentals, JavaScript, JQuery, Python, PHP, Ruby and APIs. This site is meant to expand a new developer’s vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside each course, you are given simple-to-understand instructions, helpful tips, and a user-friendly console to test out if your code is acceptable. If you make mistakes, you are given an error message and hints for completing each lesson. It’s like having an instructor looking over your shoulder the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest part of Codecademy is that all the courses are free to use, but they do offer premium account level for additional projects and advanced tutorials. The site is great for a beginner looking for the structure of traditional coursework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-avengers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeavengers.com/&quot;&gt;CODE AVENGERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code Avengers specifically designs their courses to appeal to all ages, so you know that they are going to be fun to work through. When you start a new course, you are asked a few simple questions to better tailor the tutorial to your learning environment, and you can choose whether to use video or text tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, they only offer HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Python, but they offer courses specifically designed to teach you how to build web pages, apps, or games as the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is great for beginners who want to be entertained as they learn. Honestly, who doesn’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-school&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeschool.com/&quot;&gt;CODE SCHOOL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve worked through Codecademy or Code Avengers, I recommend checking out Code School. They offer more in-depth coursework that provides a clear path and more masterful grasp on each language. Definitely one of our best coding websites for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, you can choose one of four paths for becoming an expert:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML/CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly all the courses are packed full of well-written screencasts and polished design. The challenges that follow each lesson aren’t for the weak-willed, so consider yourself warned. Luckily there are hints to help you along the way. While most courses are free, some will prompted you to upgrade to a premium account in order to finish the entire course. For a small subscription fee, you get access to all the courses across the entire site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;treehouse&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;TREEHOUSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like to master big concepts by building real projects, such as a responsive website, WordPress theme or application, Treehouse is a great place to learn programming with a purpose. You can build a foundation of knowledge in their vast offering of courses with a video + quiz format, each broken out into stages or modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get past the first stage, however, you will be prompted to upgrade to a premium account for a small subscription fee. If you are serious about your coding chops at this point, this is a good investment as you get access to all 650+ videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lyndacom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/&quot;&gt;LYNDA.COM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I lied to you… Lynda.com might be the most well-known site on this list. Please forgive me. Do we need to hug it out? No? Good. As you may know, Lynda.com is now owned and run by LinkedIn.com, so if you choose this route, consider wearing pants when logged in. Or not…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know or will soon find out, learning a programming language is like getting a tattoo, once you get one, you want to be covered in ink from head to toe by the end of the month… but it never happens. If you want to fall down an endless well of programming languages on Lynda.com, it CAN happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynda.com offers over 121 programming languages, 400 different courses and nearly 18,000 video tutorials for their Web Developer track alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy shenanigans, Batman, all that for free?! Well, not exactly. You can try it out with a free 10-day trial and get unlimited access to their coursework and featured experts. If you want to make a small investment in continuous learning, check out Lynda.com as an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t get a tattoo on there, but you can permanently “ink” some serious language knowledge in your brain. While this is definitely one of the better coding websites for beginners, this route is definitely for someone who has a developed a little chops and looking to take their coding game to 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;learn-how-to-code-today-save-the-universe-tomorrow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEARN HOW TO CODE TODAY, SAVE THE UNIVERSE TOMORROW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are looking to advance your career, supplement your skill set, or just love to learn, these five coding websites for beginners offer instant and interactive courses to teach you programming languages like HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, PHP, and Ruby. From videos, screencasts and tutorials, you will be taught best practices by industry professionals and programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows, it could be your first step toward mastering a programming language, changing your entire life, meeting the person of your dreams, raising a few unicorns, and possibly saving the entire “frakking” universe…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Whether you are looking to advance your career, supplement your skill set, or just love to learn, these five websites below offer instant and interactive courses to teach you programming languages… for free.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">20 Tips for Landing Your First Job in Web Development</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/20-tips-for-landing-your-first-job-in-web-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="20 Tips for Landing Your First Job in Web Development" /><published>2019-04-11T20:29:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T20:29:00+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/20-tips-for-landing-your-first-job-in-web-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/20-tips-for-landing-your-first-job-in-web-development/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to break into a web development career? Great decision - the job market is booming here in Austin, and around the country. In fact, there are so many jobs available that it can be overwhelming to know where to start or how to begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology field is vast, and as a result there are a variety of different career paths you can take to becoming a web developer. While there are many paths to a coding career, those who are successful shared a similar method for landing their first job in web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a fledgling techie, you can land your first job by following in the footsteps of coders before you, and use these twenty tips for success in the job market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-update-your-resume&quot;&gt;1. Update Your Resume&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you change jobs or careers, you need your resume to reflect your new career positioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Summarize your professional skills with three bullet points at the top of your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight your greatest achievements and biggest responsibilities at each previous job you’ve held.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have an eye for design, give it a nice look using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canva.com/&quot;&gt;Canva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-create-different-resumecover-letter-versions&quot;&gt;2. Create Different Resume/Cover Letter Versions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, there are a variety of different career paths into tech, so you will need a few variations of your resume to address a few different types of entry-level positions you can apply for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-start-a-blog&quot;&gt;3. Start a Blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only will you become a better developer from the amounts of research that goes into writing, but blogging also showcases your depth of knowledge, areas of interest, and establishes your brand voice. It can also set you apart from your competition. Anyone can “fake it” on a resume or portfolio, but a blog is another substantial piece of evidence that you are the real deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-examine-your-interests&quot;&gt;4. Examine your interests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deciding to go with the first job that’s offered to you could lead to a less than desired situation. Refine your prospects only to the career path you know you’ll enjoy for longer than a week. A paycheck is great, but it won’t make you happy at work. Daniel Pink’s research on autonomy, mastery, and purpose is a great guide, if you’re looking for a model of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-build-your-online-network&quot;&gt;5. Build Your Online Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not on LinkedIn yet? Start there. Already have a profile? Make sure it reflects your new career positioning, and then start connecting with other like-minded folks in the tech industry. If you are in a coding school like ours, start connecting with other students, instructors, and alumni. Once you get the ball rolling, your networking door into the tech industry should open pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-network-in-real-life&quot;&gt;6. Network in Real Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network as much as possible. Getting to know the people that have already succeeded and learning from them is a great way to get your foot in the door and possibly find a mentor. There are tons of tech-focused meetups on Meetup.com, and if you are interested in attending one of our coding schools’ events, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/calendar&quot;&gt;events calendar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-find-a-mentor-in-the-industry&quot;&gt;7. Find a Mentor in the Industry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you followed every tip in this post, you will be well-prepared for landing a job. However, if I had to choose only three tips from this list to share, this would be one of them. There is no better way to know how to succeed in getting a job than from being coached up by a seasoned veteran of the industry. You can find mentors within your existing networks, or at meetups and networking events around town. I found my mentor on my soccer team, and it was one of the most valuable steps I took to getting my first job in web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-take-online-coding-challenges&quot;&gt;8. Take Online Coding Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At our coding school, we recommend our students practice coding at least two hours per day in order to retain and master the skills we teach. This is no different for anyone looking for a job. Most technical job processes involve at least a coding challenge or whiteboard question in order to test your chops. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefights.com/&quot;&gt;Code Fights.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-practice-whiteboarding-challenges&quot;&gt;9. Practice Whiteboarding Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told before my in-person job interview there would be no whiteboarding challenge… until there was one. Having to solve a problem on a whiteboard in front of a group of people can be terrifying. Many times, the problem is nearly unsolvable, and the interviewers just want to hear how you think. Even if you don’t know the answer, walk through your approach to the problem and how you would solve it out loud. If your logic is sound, it won’t matter if you nail the answer or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-continue-growing-your-knowledge-base&quot;&gt;10. Continue Growing Your Knowledge Base&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been looking at job postings, you know that even junior web developers are required to know more than just HTML/CSS/JavaScript. Continue to grow your coding knowledge base - learn another language, framework, or library. Bootstrap and Foundation are great CSS frameworks, while Angular2, React, .NET, or Node.js are also highly in demand in JS and C# circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-build-your-own-project&quot;&gt;11. Build Your Own Project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies want to hire someone actively passionate and proactive about writing code. Work on an app or website that keeps your skills and areas of interest sharp. Love cooking? Design a website for a bakery or restaurant and showcase your culinary skills. Love animals? Build a website for a veterinary hospital non-profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-never-stop-working-on-your-online-portfolio-site&quot;&gt;12. Never Stop Working On Your Online Portfolio Site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you followed the previous tip, you just expanded your skillset and now have even more powerful tools at your fingertips. Make sure your portfolio site reflects these new skillsets and continue to update it with the latest and greatest code you know how to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;13-contribute-and-collaborate-on-github-projects&quot;&gt;13. Contribute and Collaborate on Github Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web developers need to work well in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/why-our-coding-bootcamp-teaches-you-more-than-just-code&quot;&gt;collaborative environment and know how to contribute to projects meaningfully.&lt;/a&gt; Every recruiter and hiring manager you communicate with will most likely review your Github profile and repos to see how much experience you have with these teamwork-based skills. It’s also a great way to grow your skillsets and projects featured on your portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;14-spend-as-much-time-as-possible-per-day-job-searching&quot;&gt;14. Spend As Much Time As Possible Per Day Job Searching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard this mantra before: Finding a job is a full-time job. It’s true. Job searching is a combination of networking, applying for jobs, and working with recruiters, with networking being the most effective activity. It takes time, effort, and a certain amount of preparation to not only get a job, but get one you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;15-refine-your-job-search&quot;&gt;15. Refine Your Job Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refine your search to industries and companies you would actually work for. While it may feel rewarding to blast your CV to every junior position available on the market, be honest with yourself about what type of industries you want to work in. Finding a job is hard work, so every ounce of time and effort you put into it should be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;16-apply-through-a-referral&quot;&gt;16. Apply through a Referral&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take advantage of your network and apply for a job through someone who works at the company. Some of the best jobs I’ve ever had I landed through someone I know inside my network. In fact, both development jobs I’ve had came via someone I knew who already worked at the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;17-apply-directly-with-a-company&quot;&gt;17. Apply Directly With a Company.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t fall into the habit of using the “Easy Apply” button on LinkedIn, or applying indirectly through a third-party job board. Chances are highly likely that a company who is hiring on a job board also has it posted on their website, with a way to apply directly with them. These applications are commonly vetted first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;18-research-companies-you-interview-with&quot;&gt;18. Research Companies You Interview With&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going in for an interview, do some background research on the folks you’ve been told are involved in the interviewing process (ex: LinkedIn profiles). Knowing an interesting fact about the interviewer - what college they went to, did they play a sport or part of a club - can be an instant icebreaker and shows your level of interest not only in the company, but in the people you could potentially work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;19-practice-relevant-interview-questions&quot;&gt;19. Practice Relevant Interview Questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research job forums for common and potential interview questions and coding challenges for the positions you are applying for. Practice answering these questions and coding challenges correctly, and research any topics or challenges you don’t feel confident in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;20-send-a-personalized-thank-you-note&quot;&gt;20. Send a Personalized “Thank You” Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel like you nailed an interview and want to work for the company, consider sending a handwritten “thank you” note or personalized email as a follow-up. This doesn’t work every time or at every company, but I’ve seen it work as the difference-maker between two equally-viewed applicants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landing your first job as a web developer isn’t easy, but you can definitely do it with the right amount of effort in a few focused areas. You spend around 2,000 hours per year at your job. Make sure you are doing all you can to set yourself up for success in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">While there are many paths to a coding career, those who are successful shared a similar method for landing their first job in web development. As a fledgling techie, you can land your first job by following in the footsteps of coders before you, and use these twenty tips for success in the job market.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Benefits of an In-Person Coding Bootcamp vs. Online Classes</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/the-benefits-of-an-in-person-coding-bootcamp-vs-online-classes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Benefits of an In-Person Coding Bootcamp vs. Online Classes" /><published>2019-03-04T21:22:15+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T21:22:15+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/the-benefits-of-an-in-person-coding-bootcamp-vs-online-classes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/the-benefits-of-an-in-person-coding-bootcamp-vs-online-classes/">&lt;p&gt;With the rise of coding bootcamps as a pathway into the world of tech, there are a lot of options to choose from. One of the most important decisions to make is whether you want to attend an in-person class or an online bootcamp. While both options provide their own advantages, in-person classes tend to provide better outcomes for students for a variety of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-breakdown-in-person-vs-online-coding&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Breakdown: In-Person vs. Online Coding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing between in-person and online bootcamps is an important decision that will shape your coding skill set. Your learning experience will influence both your opinion of the coding education service and coding in general. A bad programming learning experience can turn people away from coding altogether. Here are the benefits of in-person coding bootcamps compared to online classes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;access-to-support&quot;&gt;Access to Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While online classes may be more accessible in certain cases, they lack essential elements that are important when learning a new skill. Most important among these is &lt;strong&gt;support.&lt;/strong&gt; When learning a skill that is as involved as coding, it’s crucial to have support for when you get stuck – because you will get stuck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be incredibly difficult to simulate support in an online class, but it is a key component of the in-person experience. Having the ability to get live feedback from instructors and tutors can accelerate and improve the learning process, eliminate frustration, and allow for the exchange of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;3px&quot; height=&quot;2px&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/giving-coding-help.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A woman helping a man on his computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wealth and depth of information that is available when learning to code can be a blessing and a curse. Many developers will tell you that the ability to &lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt; is a key part of their day-to-day job. It may sound silly, but it’s true! Developers share knowledge with each other regularly, meaning there are plenty of answers on the web. This, however, can make it difficult and overwhelming to learn as a beginner. Where should you go for information? How do you know that the particular video you watched or article you read is a best practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these cases, there is no substitute for having the guidance of a professional to help you work through the problems that you’re having. Not only can they give you the answers that you need and direct you to strong, reliable online resources, they can help you solve problems through real life coding, which brings us to the next benefit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practical-application&quot;&gt;Practical Application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of learning a new skill, and especially one that is going to be the center of your new career, nothing is more important than practical application. The core goal of the coding bootcamp experience is to make sure that students are ready to land a job after graduating. Employers value the ability to understand high-level concepts, but at the end of the day, if you can’t apply the concepts to real life code, no one is going to hire you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like support, it is hard to simulate genuine practical projects through online classes. When opting for an in-person experience, you open up the world of guided coding, immediate feedback on project builds, and more. Even with the best online curriculums, it’s impossible to have the same level of responsiveness and guidance as an in-person classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;peer-collaboration&quot;&gt;Peer Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important advantage that in-person coding classes have over online options are that they allow for real life collaboration with peers in a classroom setting. Similar to having the support of instructors and tutors, being able to collaborate and build with peers improves the learning process significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning coding is an &lt;strong&gt;iterative process&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that it is best learned by doing, (often failing), and doing again. The value of having peers beside you who are going through the same process cannot be understated. It can be lonely to feel like you aren’t grasping a concept fast enough. Classmates are able to relate, provide their own unique perspectives and strengths, and help as you break down barriers. Not to mention, you’ll leave with the added benefit of having built a network of peers and friends that can help you in your future career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-pace-of-online-coding-bootcamps-can-leave-you-behind&quot;&gt;The Pace of Online Coding Bootcamps Can Leave You Behind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, many online or immersive coding bootcamps sell the idea that you can learn to be a web developer in just weeks. While this may sound attractive to someone who’s looking to switch careers, these expedited courses generally don’t allow for students to absorb the extensive amount of material required to become an effective and job-ready software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about any new skill that you’ve ever learned. Would you say that you’re willing to be a professional in it after a few weeks of study? Probably not. Web development, like anything else, is a skill that can be learned and developed. While you may be able to pick up some information over the course of a few weeks, real learning and competency comes from practice, application, and repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;3px&quot; height=&quot;2px&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/javascript-html-css-books.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Books on JavaScript, HTML, CSS&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to these programs, in-person classes generally tend to be slower than online coding schools. A less frantic pace allows for exploration and helps the learning of a vast amount of resources sink in and stick rather than rushing through material only to forget most of it shortly afterward. For this reason, in-person grads tend to be more well-rounded and job-ready candidates after graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary-in-person-coding-bootcamps-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary: In-Person Coding Bootcamps&lt;/strong&gt; ✅&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both options have some pros and cons to weigh out before choosing. Depending on what your learning style is, in-person coding courses could be the right fit for you. In-person coding bootcamps have some strong advantages that play off of student’s strengths and shore up their weaknesses more effectively than their online counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In learning programming languages or any other subject for that matter, motivation is key to succeeding. Having &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hyperiondev.com/index.php/2019/01/15/online-vs-person-coding-bootcamps-one-best/&quot;&gt;fellow learners&lt;/a&gt; and instructors around can help bolster motivation and ensures that you won’t fall behind. Online coding bootcamps can be less expensive, however, they are also less structured and make even the most prompt of online instructors feel out of reach. Furthermore, working in teams is one of the most important aspects of efficient coding, and in-person bootcamps allow for richer teamwork experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the superior structuring and level of student interaction make in-person coding bootcamps the way to go for most students. These pros make in-person bootcamps a better choice for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are considering joining a coding bootcamp, consider Austin Coding Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-your-experience-learning-to-code-a-good-one-austin-coding-academy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Your Experience Learning to Code a Good One: Austin Coding Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Austin Coding Academy we make sure that students get the best possible in-person experience, through three key components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Our flipped-classroom approach project-based curriculum give you the practical experience that companies are looking for from bootcamp graduates. All of our students graduate with a full-built application that they can use in interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Unlimited tutoring is available to all of our students. As long as you’re willing to put in the hours to learn, we make sure that you have the support to work through any problems that you may encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Job placement is our number one priority. We have a Director of Job Placement who works with each of our students individually, and a 4-week Job Placement course to make sure that every single graduate is supported as they launch their new career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interested in learning to code with Austin Coding Academy? You can learn about the courses we have to offer, our job placement strategy, and more at&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;austincodingacademy.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. If you’re ready to get started, you can fill out a quick, 5-minute application and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;apply now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With the rise of coding bootcamps as a pathway into the world of tech, there are a lot of options to choose from. One of the most important decisions to make is whether you want to attend an in-person class or an online bootcamp. While both options provide their own advantages, here is why you should opt for an in-person experience:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Four Exciting Projects That Will Inspire You to Learn JavaScript Right Now</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Four Exciting Projects That Will Inspire You to Learn JavaScript Right Now" /><published>2019-02-24T20:14:48+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-24T20:14:48+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript-right-now-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/javascript/four-exciting-projects-that-will-inspire-you-to-learn-javascript/">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript (JS) is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackify.com/popular-programming-languages-2018/&quot;&gt;most commonly-used coding language&lt;/a&gt; for developers in 2019. JS earned its popularity because it’s easy to learn, dynamically typed, fast to run, and works across most platforms, including all modern web browsers. Coders &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/which-aca-track-is-right-for-you&quot;&gt;from all different specialties&lt;/a&gt; will need a basic understanding of JavaScript to complete most designs—especially front-end designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some impressive projects that might inspire you to want to start learning JavaScript now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-technology-and-talking-plants&quot;&gt;Smart technology and talking plants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart technology has the potential to improve our healthcare, revolutionize our workplaces, and customize our homes. As this trend in smart tech progresses, we may find ourselves living in a sci-fi utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One appealing smart-tech project uses JavaScript code to create &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webondevices.com/the-arduino-plant-with-javascript-voice-recognition/&quot;&gt;smart plants&lt;/a&gt;. Smart plants use sensors to detect soil moisture, temperature, and other factors important for plant health. Advanced voice recognition software and text-to-voice capability makes it easy to interact with smart plants and simplifies the plant maintenance process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart technology is an emerging field that will soon change our lives. Learning JavaScript could provide you with the skill set necessary to land a job in this new and exciting industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drones-that-fly-themselves&quot;&gt;Drones that fly themselves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drones aren’t just fun; they’re useful, with applications in aerial photography, package deliveries, safety inspections, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virgin.com/virgin-unite/business-innovation/humanitarian-sky-drones-disaster-response&quot;&gt;humanitarian efforts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using JavaScript, it’s possible to build self-driving drones. Lines of JS code can command drones to auto-hover, perform barrel rolls, and run into red objects like a matador would do with a bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At events like &lt;a href=&quot;http://dronegames.co/&quot;&gt;Drone Games&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nodecopter.com/&quot;&gt;Nodecopter&lt;/a&gt;, programmers use software to see who can make the coolest drone. They often reuse open-source code snippets to program features like voice to text, face recognition, and advanced directional 3D movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these projects are fun, they can also help you land a job. The drone job market will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/budget-finance/Drone-Related-Job-Growth-to-Outpace-Predictions.html&quot;&gt;grow faster than predicted&lt;/a&gt;, and some universities even offer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/budget-finance/Drone-Related-Job-Growth-to-Outpace-Predictions.html&quot;&gt;degrees in drone technology&lt;/a&gt;. Industries that will use drones include the military, real estate, construction, filmmaking, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://uavcoach.com/uav-jobs/#guide-5&quot;&gt;insurance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about what it takes to get into the drone industry by reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.ieee.org/jobs/content/Drones-are-a-big-job-opportunity-but-for-new-engin-2017-02-10&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-apps-that-dominate-industries&quot;&gt;Mobile apps that dominate industries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brainhub.eu/blog/famous-apps-built-with-react-native/&quot;&gt;Many apps&lt;/a&gt; use the JS react native framework, but the Facebook ads app is a particularly shining example. &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.fb.com/developer-tools/react-native-for-android-how-we-built-the-first-cross-platform-react-native-app/&quot;&gt;Facebook uses JS&lt;/a&gt; to calculate complex variables like ad formats, time zones, dates, and currencies. Many of these features are accessible through an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.mybridge.co/amazing-javascript-projects-for-the-past-year-v-2018-2f114c6bd70a&quot;&gt;open source JavaScript code&lt;/a&gt;. The react native framework is also perfect for creating an integrated user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When tech giants like Facebook use JS, it shows that the language is not limited to small app projects. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/blogs/5-benefits-of-reactjs-to-brighten-a-cloudy-day&quot;&gt;JavaScript has key advantages&lt;/a&gt; that make it perfect for projects of any size. Learning JS can help developers build projects at any scale—big or small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;websites-to-inspire-action&quot;&gt;Websites to inspire action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website design skills are growing in demand. Companies spend a lot of time and money trying to drive traffic to their website. Designers who can convert that traffic into paying customers are especially competitive in the job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is the perfect tool for building &lt;a href=&quot;http://webdesignerwall.com/trends/30-truly-interactive-websites-built-css-javascript&quot;&gt;stunning websites.&lt;/a&gt; The code is fast, and object manipulation makes it possible to create amazing interactive designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning JavaScript will prepare you for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-developer&quot;&gt;lucrative career&lt;/a&gt;, but you don’t have to wait until after graduation to get started. Working on side projects is a great way to hone your skills and build up your &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-are-hiring-managers-looking-for-in-a-developers-portfolio&quot;&gt;developer’s portfolio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some amazing websites to inspire your next web-design project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://windowwonderland.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;Window Wonderland&lt;/a&gt;: This website puts you right in the middle of New York City’s holiday shopping experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cavalierchallenge.com/&quot;&gt;Cavalier Challenge&lt;/a&gt;: This online game immerses you in a experience right from the get-go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airview.blueair.com/&quot;&gt;Air View&lt;/a&gt;: Air View is an innovative way to visualize abstract air quality data to make it feel “real.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keyideas.net/&quot;&gt;Key Ideas&lt;/a&gt;: Key Ideas is a film-production agency that uses their website to showcase their unique skills and services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some ACA students who made projects with JavaScript to improve their portfolio and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/5-ways-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austins-tech-industry&quot;&gt;land their first developer job&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/student-project-highlight-jon-gucciardi&quot;&gt;Jon Gucciardi&lt;/a&gt; built his own messaging app, and landed a job as a software developer for Verizon Wireless.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/student-project-highlight-greg-devany&quot;&gt;Greg Devany&lt;/a&gt; designed a website and app for helping users find coupons for restaurants. He’s used it as the cornerstone of his resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-learning-javascript-today&quot;&gt;Start learning JavaScript today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These projects highlight why JavaScript is such a desirable skill to have. JavaScript developers get to work on fun tasks while earning &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-will-you-make-as-a-full-time-developer&quot;&gt;a great salary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACA offers you the fast track to a coding career. You’ll learn the most in-demand skills from teachers who also work full-time as developers. After graduation, you’ll get access to our job placement network to connect you with the position of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to start your path towards a rewarding career? &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;Apply today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://acaappointment.acuityscheduling.com/schedule.php?appointmentType=1406673&quot;&gt;schedule a call with our staff&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.austincodingacademy.com/schedule-a-campus-tour&quot;&gt;tour the campus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com&quot;&gt;Learn how ACA can help&lt;/a&gt; jumpstart your software development career today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">JavaScript (JS) is the most commonly-used coding language for developers in 2019. JS earned its popularity because it’s easy to learn, dynamically typed, fast to run, and works across most platforms, including all modern web browsers. Let’s look at some impressive projects that might inspire you to start learning JavaScript now:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What to Do When You Want to Change Careers</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/what-to-do-when-you-want-to-change-careers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What to Do When You Want to Change Careers" /><published>2019-02-21T21:32:48+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T21:32:48+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/what-to-do-when-you-want-to-change-careers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/career-development/what-to-do-when-you-want-to-change-careers/">&lt;p&gt;The thought of changing careers is exciting to many people at one time or another. With your goals and ambitions no longer constrained by your old career path, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/5-signs-you-need-to-change-careers&quot;&gt;a career change&lt;/a&gt; may open up your potential and let you surprise yourself. Pursuing a career you’re excited about can also provide a stronger sense of purpose and passion for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that excitement can vanish if you’re afraid changing careers is too risky or complicated. The truth is, you don’t have to take irresponsible risks when exploring new career options. You can even prepare for a career change while &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/&quot;&gt;keeping your current job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some strategies that can help you make a transition without the risk of going broke:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-clear-about-what-you-want&quot;&gt;Be clear about what you want&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to go to all the effort of changing careers, only to fall into another career you dislike. That’s why it’s critical you consider what career factors do you value most. With a clear idea of what you want, you can better choose a profession that’s in line with your goals and aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, use the experience from your current job to pinpoint what to avoid in a future career. Open a document or grab a piece of paper and write down a list of the exact tasks you dislike in your current role. Think critically about WHY you don’t enjoy these tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of why you may not like a task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skill mismatch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much/too little human interaction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feels unrewarding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tasks are too repetitive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack autonomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now repeat the process, but list the tasks at your job you actually enjoy (come on… there must be &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; you like). Again, ask why you enjoy these tasks. You can now use these two lists to help determine what you are looking for from a new line of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider is the impact your new career will have on the rest of your life. Here are some examples questions to ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you want to work from home?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the option of starting a business important?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What income level do you want to achieve?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you want absolute choice over where you live?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What job outlook are you comfortable with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorm-careers&quot;&gt;Brainstorm careers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand what’s important to you, brainstorm some careers that will give you what you want. The key to effective brainstorming is to think openly about your potential new direction. Remember to think about why you liked the tasks you listed above. Don’t limit yourself because of preconceived notions of what you think a career is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebalance.com/free-career-aptitude-tests-2059813&quot;&gt;taking a free aptitude test&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com/advice/8-brilliant-books-that-will-lead-you-to-your-dream-job&quot;&gt;reading a career book&lt;/a&gt;. Explore websites like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/ooh/&quot;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics&lt;/a&gt; to get a better idea of career outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our students love coding because it’s a career that offers the flexibility to work wherever you want. It is also highly in demand, making it a high-paying career field. ACA students earn an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.switchup.org/bootcamps/austin-coding-academy&quot;&gt;average starting salary of $64,000&lt;/a&gt;. For entrepreneurial types, there are also a lot of ways to branch off and start your own projects/businesses with coding skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reach-out-to-people-in-your-desired-field&quot;&gt;Reach out to people in your desired field&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An underrated strategy for &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/5-ways-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austins-tech-industry&quot;&gt;exploring new work&lt;/a&gt; is connecting with mentors. Talking to friends and family is great if they’re in your exact field of interest. For most of us, that won’t be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you’ll want to reach out to people who’ve already accomplished what you want to do. If you’re looking to become a developer, you can always connect with &lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/austin-coding-academy-1&quot;&gt;ACA’s alumni network&lt;/a&gt;. Another way to network with professionals in your desired field is to reach out to them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Google or Indeed/LinkedIn to find companies that hire your desired position.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the people currently in the position you want by searching directory pages or the employee section of Linkedin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send them an email or ask to “connect” if on LinkedIn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask them questions about their career choice to see if it’s the right choice for you too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this can be useful information, take their feedback with a grain of salt, because many people tend to speak highly of their own careers. When you reach out like this, it often makes people feel like their work is important (and by extension, that &lt;em&gt;they’re&lt;/em&gt; important). They probably wouldn’t want to lose face by confessing to a stranger that their job sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some questions to ask questions to get honest answers without forcing them to either sugarcoat the truth about their jobs or hurt their ego:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What daily task do you like most at your job?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What task do you like the least?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What personality traits would someone need to be good at this job?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is one thing you wish you knew before starting your career?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s one big misconception you had about the field before you started?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;try-it-out-first&quot;&gt;Try it out first&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve done a lot of prep work at this point. Now it’s time to get your hands dirty and actually do some work in the position you’re interested in. It’s easy to fantasize about why a career might be amazing, but actually doing the work will give you a more accurate idea of what it takes. A test run is important to understand if you’re getting into the right field before investing too much time or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get started with the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take an introduction class (here’s some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/o/austin-coding-academy-10937668459&quot;&gt;great local events&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take freelance work on job sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/&quot;&gt;upwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask the people you emailed for internship opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re ready, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/blog/2017/05/26/20-tips-for-landing-your-first-job-in-web-development&quot;&gt;get an entry-level job&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;commit-to-change&quot;&gt;Commit to change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve decided on your career and given it a test run, it’s time to commit. Look up the career paths by using a tool like the “Common Career Paths” section on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.payscale.com/research/US/Job=Web_Developer/Salary&quot;&gt;PayScale&lt;/a&gt;. This is helpful to get a better idea of what you want your long-term career to look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now take time to invest in your education. Start learning everything you can to be competent in your field. Make sure to learn practical skills that will be attractive to employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great option for educating yourself is to &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;take a class&lt;/a&gt;. At ACA, you’ll be able to learn the skills to get a coding job you love. You also get the added benefit of support from your peers and teachers to help you succeed and access to a network of experienced professionals required to help land an amazing job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to jump into an exciting coding career &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;apply today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The thought of changing careers is exciting to many people at one time or another. With your goals and ambitions no longer constrained by your old career path, a career change may open up your potential and let you surprise yourself. But that excitement can vanish if you’re afraid changing careers is too risky or complicated. Here are some strategies that can help you make a transition while minimizing risk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Characteristics of a Successful Web Developer</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Characteristics of a Successful Web Developer" /><published>2019-02-21T21:04:26+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T21:04:26+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/7-characteristics-of-a-successful-web-developer/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanstenis/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Stenis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;graduated from Austin Coding Academy’s Full Stack Web Development program in 2016. Upon graduating, Luke landed a role as an “Implementation Engineer” with Austin-based content production company,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invodo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. During his time at Invodo, Luke also worked as an instructor at ACA, teaching the 10-week “Intro to Web Development” course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke currently works in Salt Lake City, Utah, as a “Digital Analytics Implementation Engineer” with&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pluralsight.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PluralSight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there certain characteristics that make you a better web developer than others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking into the tech scene can be very intimidating - it seems like every day there is a trendy new JS library to learn and another class of coding school graduates to compete with. If you spend any time scouring job boards, you’ll also see this reflected in entry-level or junior web development jobs requiring a wider knowledge base from their applicants than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, you would think that candidates with the deepest ocean of knowledge would always land the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may come as a surprise to you – as the web developer role spends most of their time in front of a computer screen, handling highly technical issues with complicated code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, I’ve been on both sides of the hiring process for tech roles, and have witnessed the smartest candidates get passed over for someone who is a better “fit” for the role or company. I’ve seen the sharpest web developers crumble and crack under the pressure of deadlines, or lose their patience and professionalism from constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great code doesn’t always translate into a great hire. While it definitely helps, there is more to being a successful web developer than a mind rich in technical knowledge. Here are seven characteristics common in web developers - other than technical skills - who are successful at their job:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-passion-for-knowledge&quot;&gt;A passion for knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology is always evolving, and the skills and abilities needed in today’s tech scene can get outdated quickly. It’s important to have a passion for learning and the desire to keep up with the latest trends. As newer versions of languages, libraries and frameworks roll out, you will be expected to not only know these changes, but be a subject matter expert within your company. Don’t confuse this with technical skills - you can still love to learn without being the sharpest crayon in the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes beyond a willingness to educate yourself. You should embrace the inevitable challenges that come with the job, and develop a great habit for researching possible solutions. If you love the work and the challenge that it presents, you will be successful at your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-teammate&quot;&gt;Great teammate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web developer rarely works alone. Good software is commonly built by a whole development team comprised of many dynamic roles. Being able to take on a team mentality can be critical to the success of a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the immediate team, web developers will also be expected to work with business owners, sales and marketing staff, and other developers outside of the team or company in order to achieve a wider project scope. In these cases, the ability to lead or act as the representative of your team in a meeting or other professional scenario is a soft skill that helps you stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creative-problem-solver&quot;&gt;Creative problem solver&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing code for a software program or designing website from scratch is incredibly difficult – much like trying to solve a complex math equation or write a novel. A great developer thrives on finding ways to make things work, no matter the challenge, and sometimes needs to get creative to find a working solution. You want to try to avoid the phrase “It can’t be done” when you are pitched a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great working knowledge of the language or framework you are using is a must. If you understand the limitations or abilities of the code you are using, you can awaken more creative and efficient ideas for solving problems. And the light bulbs will turn on faster and brighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ability-to-plan-for-everything&quot;&gt;Ability to plan for everything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than jumping head-first into a project, a wise and cautious web developer will first learn as much as possible about the desired end product. Once this step is completed, the developer will then plan out the entire structure of the project before typing out one line of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a critical step - as one little oversight can throw a project deadline off by weeks or even months. Complete your wireframe the entire site and get approval before creating your first template. Ensure your routes and controllers are properly configured. If you don’t properly plan for as much as possible, you better have…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-debugging-skills&quot;&gt;Great debugging skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my current job, I identify and solve issues on large, e-commerce websites. Basically, I help fix bad code written by their in-house developers that they couldn’t solve themselves. What I found more shocking than how simple the mistakes are – was how often the developers themselves did not know how to properly debug their own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing and developing code is only part of a web developer’s job. They are also expected to identify the root of a problem quickly and effectively. Instead of spending hours making blind changes, developers need to have a solid handle on the variety of Web Developer Tools provided by modern browsers such as Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and Edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accelerated-failure-mentality&quot;&gt;“Accelerated Failure” Mentality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fail Fast”, “Fail Better”, “Fail Forward” are all popular mantras used by startups and tech giants in Silicon Valley. If you aren’t failing, you aren’t learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rarely does code get written correctly the first time. This is why we plan for everything and know how to debug anything. It’s important to see bugs and errors in your code as a challenge rather than a sign of defeat. Successful web developers embrace the challenge of failure and tend to bounce back with bigger and better solutions to these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business-sense&quot;&gt;Business Sense&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;300px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-5-31-17-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great developer can look beyond the project they are working on and see the big picture for the business. A savvy business sense can lead to new applications or automated processes focused on more saving time and money for a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to an MBA or a passion for macro-economics to be business-savvy, but showing an interest in areas of the business outside of your direct scope can lead to a better understanding of your company’s big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t easy becoming a web developer - and to excel in the industry takes more than an encyclopedia of coding knowledge. There are certain characteristics that successful web developers share not commonly taught in many CS degree programs or coding schools. You need to have a variety of soft skills on top of your technical abilities to stand out in the crowd when applying for a job in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching these soft skills is one way our program stands out in the crowd of coding schools. Our program not only teach our students the technical skills every full-stack web developer needs, every campus provide workshops and break-out sessions in order to provide a wider educational foundation in soft skills proven to help any fledgling web developer succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning both the hard and soft skills necessary for a successful coding career, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/courses/&quot;&gt;course schedule&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://austincodingacademy.com/apply/&quot;&gt;fill out an application&lt;/a&gt; to save your spot in the next class.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Great code doesn’t always translate into a great hire. While it definitely helps, there is more to being a successful web developer than a mind rich in technical knowledge. Here are seven characteristics common in web developers - other than technical skills - who are successful at their job:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Get a Job as a Web Developer in Austin’s Tech Industry</title><link href="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/how-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austin-tech-industry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Get a Job as a Web Developer in Austin's Tech Industry" /><published>2019-02-21T20:59:29+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T20:59:29+00:00</updated><id>https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/how-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austin-s-tech-industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://austincodingacademy.com/blog/web-development/how-to-get-a-job-as-a-web-developer-in-austin-tech-industry/">&lt;p&gt;Looking for your first web development job in Austin can seem extremely daunting. This is especially true if you are new to town and don’t have a built-in network of friends to help you get a foot in the door at a tech company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fear not! We’ve rounded up some great resources and events that can help you find a web development job in Austin. Take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-go-to-career-fairs&quot;&gt;1. Go to Career Fairs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Career fairs are a great opportunity to get a feel for different companies. Unlike submitting an application and hoping you hear back from an employer, career fairs allow you to meet recruiters and managers in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a little facetime gives you the opportunity to sharing your personality and enthusiasm with potential employers. This connection is much more valuable than all the stats listed in plethora of applications buried in their email folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-use-job-boards-to-find-web-development-jobs-in-austin&quot;&gt;2. Use Job Boards to Find Web Development Jobs in Austin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can always type “web development jobs in Austin” on Monster, LinkedIn, Indeed, and other popular job sites. But if you haven’t noticed yet, these sites are getting very saturated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more tailored results, here are the places to look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-web-designers-and-developers&quot;&gt;For Web Designers and Developers:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.authenticjobs.com/&quot;&gt;Authentic Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://angel.co/jobs&quot;&gt;Angel List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upwork.com/&quot;&gt;UpWork&lt;/a&gt; (formerly elance and odesk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.krop.com/&quot;&gt;Krop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startupers.com/&quot;&gt;Startupers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://weworkremotely.com/&quot;&gt;We Work Remotely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-web-developers&quot;&gt;For Web Developers:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://careers.stackoverflow.com/jobs&quot;&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jobs.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://androidjobs.io/&quot;&gt;Android Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jobs.coreint.org/&quot;&gt;Core Intuition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-build-out-your-professional-network-both-online-and-in-person&quot;&gt;3. Build Out Your Professional Network, Both Online and In Person&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be surprised how often people land jobs through their network. The cliche “It’s not &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know but &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you know” is so common for reason. Getting an awesome web development job in Austin means building your online network and going to meetups. If you’re already doing those things, kudos. You’re killing it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re new to the scene, here are some groups and meetups you should check out to start meeting other movers and shakers in Austin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Austin-Web-Design/&quot;&gt;Austin Refresh Meetups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Austin-Coding-Academy/&quot;&gt;Austin Coding Academy Meetups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://capitalfactory.com/events/&quot;&gt;Capital Factory Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/austindigitaljobs/&quot;&gt;Austin Digital Jobs Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thebashh.com/&quot;&gt;B.A.S.H.H. (Big Ass Social Happy Hour)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-find-a-mentor-in-the-industry&quot;&gt;4. Find a Mentor in the Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’re rubbing elbows in Austin’s development community and your LinkedIn network is growing, it’s time to find a mentor in the tech industry. But be careful not to be a phony; make sure you are building genuine relationships with people you trust and admire. When it comes to asking for help from a more established person in the industry, here’s a good rule of thumb: aim to &lt;em&gt;add&lt;/em&gt; value first and &lt;em&gt;ask&lt;/em&gt; for value second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you feel like you’ve connected with someone in the industry, try experimenting with small asks until you can build up to asking for an in-person meetup over a coffee or a pint. Use this time to casually discuss your job search, your skill set, and provide insights about what kind of career opportunities you’re looking for. Their experience in the Austin tech scene can give you an inside track, especially when it comes to the interviewing process. They can also point you in the direction of more specialized events, meetups, online communities, or other resources that might help you on your path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/kathycaprino/2014/09/21/how-to-find-a-great-mentor-first-dont-ever-ask-a-stranger/&quot;&gt;Here’s a great guide&lt;/a&gt; to connecting with possible mentors through social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-practice-mock-interviews-and-questions&quot;&gt;5. Practice Mock Interviews and Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a mentor and have built a good rapport, you may want to ask to practice a mock interview with them. Most likely, you will stumble a few times and eat some humble pie, but this practice can be really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub has a great resource of &lt;a href=&quot;http://h5bp.github.io/Front-end-Developer-Interview-Questions/&quot;&gt;front-end developer interview questions&lt;/a&gt;. The internet is swimming with example questions and answers, so don’t be shy with your Googlin’ skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two resources to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iI6jiwoqxg4&quot;&gt;A video&lt;/a&gt; about how to prepare for a job interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.austincodingacademy.com/what-are-hiring-managers-looking-for-in-a-developers-portfolio&quot;&gt;What hiring managers want to see in a portfolio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bonus-paid-internships&quot;&gt;Bonus: Paid Internships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still struggling to get your foot in the door, and are willing and able to put in another three months of “on-the-job” training, there are plenty of startups and tech companies (such as uShip, IBM, and Dell) that offer decent paid web development internships somewhere in the $25-$28/hour range. These companies use their internship pools for new hires, and most entry-level jobs are filled this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a full-time job finding a job, and every little advantage helps. Doing these five things will help you position yourself for not only short-term gains, but long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and may the function be with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Looking for your first web development job in Austin can seem extremely daunting. This is especially true if you are new to town and don't have a built-in network of friends to help you get you foot in the door at a tech company. Fear not! We’ve rounded up some great resources and to help. Take a look:</summary></entry></feed>